[{"question":" A dataset that includes \\_ can be used to create a map visualization. (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"A, B, C, D","correct":true},{"text":"A, C, D","correct":false},{"text":"B, C, D","correct":false},{"text":"D","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" How do you create a chart visual in Power BI Desktop Report view? (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"A, B, or D","correct":false},{"text":"B or D","correct":false},{"text":"B orC","correct":false},{"text":"A or B","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What daily sales number does this DAX measure formula calculate?","options":[{"text":"running total sales in each month that starts over each month","correct":false},{"text":"total sales for the entire month","correct":false},{"text":"running total in entire year for the entire month","correct":true},{"text":"rolling average over 12 months of sales","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You are creating a report in Power BI Desktop and want to restrict the data to records where Country=\"Canada\". To accomplish this, what do you need to create?","options":[{"text":"a directive","correct":true},{"text":"a custom column","correct":false},{"text":"an indexed column","correct":false},{"text":"a parameter","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is the primary benefit of using visualizations such as line charts, bar charts, and column charts?","options":[{"text":"They are easier to create than other visualizations.","correct":false},{"text":"They require fewer resources than more complex visualizations.","correct":true},{"text":"They are also used in Excel, so they feel familiar to users.","correct":false},{"text":"They are free to use.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" In Power BI service, deleted pages are available after deletion until","options":[{"text":"midnight of the day on which they are deleted","correct":false},{"text":"the next billing cycle","correct":false},{"text":"you empty the Recycle Bin","correct":false},{"text":"the report has been saved","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You need to add a required color to a bar chart. How can you add an exact color value to an existing bar chart?","options":[{"text":"Click the color in the visual (e.g., the bars) and right-click to select the color.","correct":true},{"text":"You cannot select custom colors in a bar chart or related visual.","correct":false},{"text":"Select the value closest to this color from the color formatting options.","correct":false},{"text":"Enter the hex value into the color formatting options.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" The Excel function IF is nearly the same as which DAX function?","options":[{"text":"SWITCH","correct":false},{"text":"IF","correct":false},{"text":"IFX","correct":true},{"text":"IFS","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Consider the Power BI extract, transform, and load process (ETL). During this process, data is read and then","options":[],"illustrator":""},{"question":"ored in S#### QL Server","options":[{"text":"written to an OLAP cube","correct":false},{"text":"assigned a data type","correct":false},{"text":"sorted by primary key","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Power BI's Publish to Web option allows you to embed visualizations within **\\_**. (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"A,C","correct":false},{"text":"C","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C, D","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What can you do within the Power BI Desktop #### Query Settings pane? (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"B, C, D","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C, D [proof link](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/transform-model/desktop-query-overview)","correct":true},{"text":"A, B, D","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". After you enter text in the #### Q&A box or O&A visual, Power BI will `\\_` your data to create a list of appropriate visualizations.","options":[{"text":"filter and group","correct":false},{"text":"sort and filter","correct":false},{"text":"sort, filter, and group","correct":false},{"text":"sort and group","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You just deleted a dashboard in the Power BI service and want to get it back. What should you do?","options":[{"text":"Press Ctrl+Z.","correct":true},{"text":"Select Undo from the toolbar.","correct":false},{"text":"You cannot undo the deletion of a dashboard.","correct":false},{"text":"Recover it from the Recycle Bin.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have a sales data source and want to relate the tables. The table that contains sales transactions is a **\\_** table that contains product information is a \\_ table .","options":[{"text":"dimension; fact","correct":false},{"text":"lookup; data","correct":false},{"text":"data; lookup","correct":true},{"text":"data; supporting","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When you are creating a formula in the Power Query Editor, what does IntelliSense provide a list of? (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"B,C","correct":false},{"text":"A, C, D","correct":true},{"text":"C,D","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to delete a dataset but the Power BI service will not let you. What is the most likely cause?","options":[{"text":"A tile on your dashboard contains data from that dataset.","correct":false},{"text":"The dataset is already being used in a published app.","correct":true},{"text":"A report contains data from that dataset.","correct":false},{"text":"The dataset is in your workspace.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". One of your data columns includes the city, state, and postal code line of a mailing address. You need to separate the fields so you can access the geospatial elements for a map visualization. What transformation should you apply?","options":[{"text":"Replace values","correct":false},{"text":"Split column","correct":true},{"text":"Modify data type","correct":false},{"text":"Best fit geospatial","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Formatting options within a visualization depend on what?","options":[{"text":"the visualization you are formatting","correct":true},{"text":"the editor you use","correct":false},{"text":"the visualization group","correct":false},{"text":"your permissions","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What tool can you use in Power BI Desktop to reduce data?","options":[{"text":"report editor","correct":false},{"text":"Power Query Editor","correct":false},{"text":"dashboard","correct":false},{"text":"data modeler","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is NOT a valid data connection type for Power BI Desktop?","options":[{"text":"Azure data","correct":false},{"text":"file data","correct":false},{"text":"relationships data","correct":true},{"text":"database data","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which data type can be uploaded directly to powerbi.com?","options":[{"text":"Excel files","correct":false},{"text":"comma-separated value (CSV) files","correct":false},{"text":"Power BI Desktop files","correct":false},{"text":"all of these answers","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does Power BI Premium provide?","options":[{"text":"Power BI Report Server","correct":false},{"text":"report sharing without a per-user licens","correct":false},{"text":"all of these answers","correct":true},{"text":"dedicated capacity for your company","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have a report in Power BI service and want to save the state of a report page for easy access. What feature helps you do this?","options":[{"text":"views","correct":true},{"text":"filters","correct":false},{"text":"bookmarks","correct":false},{"text":"slicers","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What daily sales number does this DAX measure formula calculate?","options":[{"text":"running total sales in each month that starts over each month","correct":false},{"text":"total sales for the entire month","correct":false},{"text":"running total in entire year for the entire month","correct":false},{"text":"rolling average over 12 months of sales","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What should you do to increase the readability of a report?","options":[{"text":"all of these answers","correct":true},{"text":"Remove unnecessary field labels.","correct":false},{"text":"Select the most appropriate visualization.","correct":false},{"text":"Use borders.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which feature in the Power BI service is most useful when you need to create pages that present the same visualizations for different territories, salespeople, or teams?","options":[{"text":"landscape mode","correct":false},{"text":"none of these answers","correct":false},{"text":"Shrink to Fit","correct":false},{"text":"templates","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What should you use to highlight a specific visualization in a report?","options":[{"text":"Spotlight","correct":false},{"text":"Highlight","correct":false},{"text":"Magnify","correct":false},{"text":"None of the answers","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does My Workspace on powerbi.com include?","options":[{"text":"Visualizations and a fields list","correct":false},{"text":"Toolbars and preferences","correct":false},{"text":"Workbooks and visualizations","correct":false},{"text":"Dashboards and reports","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to access the underlying data for a specific data point in a visualization. What should you choose?","options":[{"text":"Drill up","correct":false},{"text":"Drill down","correct":false},{"text":"Expand to next level","correct":false},{"text":"Collapse","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have a treemap visualization that groups by sales territory. To allow users to further analyze data for a specific territory, what filter should you apply?","options":[{"text":"Visual level","correct":false},{"text":"Page level","correct":false},{"text":"Drillthrough","correct":true},{"text":"Expand down","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Facebook, Twilio, GitHub, and MailChimp are all examples of Power BI **\\_**.","options":[{"text":"online services","correct":true},{"text":"Wiki data sources","correct":false},{"text":"database data sources","correct":false},{"text":"File data sources","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When you use Publish to Web in the Power BI service, who can view your published content?","options":[{"text":"everyone in your environment","correct":false},{"text":"anyone on the internet","correct":false},{"text":"everyone in your organization","correct":true},{"text":"only you","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The iterator functions SUMX and AVERAGEX are used to perform calculations **\\_**.","options":[{"text":"for Power BI mobile apps","correct":false},{"text":"in Power BI service rather than Power BI desktop","correct":false},{"text":"in the context of a record","correct":true},{"text":"for very large datasets","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". In Power BI Desktop Model view, what type of join will yield all results from Table 1 and any matching results from Table 2?","options":[{"text":"Right Outer Join","correct":false},{"text":"Left Outer Join","correct":false},{"text":"Left Inner Join","correct":true},{"text":"Right Inner Join","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is NOT a built-in Power BI visual?","options":[{"text":"Power KPI","correct":true},{"text":"funnel chart","correct":false},{"text":"waterfall chart","correct":false},{"text":"ArcGIS map","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to combine several CSV files into a single data file after you connect a folder. What must be true about these CSV data files? (Select all that apply.)","options":[{"text":"B, C","correct":false},{"text":"A, B, C","correct":true},{"text":"A, B, D","correct":false},{"text":"B, C, D","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". If you delete a dateset in the Power BI service, what happens to the dashboards and reports supported by the dataset?","options":[{"text":"They will be stored as static dashboards and reports.","correct":false},{"text":"They will be deleted.","correct":true},{"text":"They will be converted to image files.","correct":false},{"text":"Nothing—they will be unchanged.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which DAX function compares a column of values in Table A with a similar column in Table B, and returns the values the are not found in Table B?","options":[{"text":"COMPARE","correct":false},{"text":"FINDUNIQUE","correct":false},{"text":"EXCEPT","correct":true},{"text":"SWITCH","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Your data model includes two related tables, Customers and Orders. To determine the number of customers that have placed orders, create a measure on the **\\_** table using the **\\_** function.","options":[{"text":"Orders; DISTINCTCOUNT","correct":true},{"text":"Customers; COUNT","correct":false},{"text":"Orders; COUNT","correct":false},{"text":"Customers; DISTINCTCOUNT","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Power BI works best with tables that are **\\_**,","options":[{"text":"short and wide","correct":false},{"text":"long and skinny","correct":true},{"text":"short and skinny","correct":false},{"text":"long and wide","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have two columns of numerical data and want to create a visual to help determine if there is a relationship between them. What kind of chart is designed to do this?","options":[{"text":"bar chart","correct":true},{"text":"bubble chart","correct":false},{"text":"line chart","correct":false},{"text":"scatter chart","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". In the report editor, which task can you NOT accomplish using drag and drop?","options":[{"text":"Add more information to a visualization.","correct":false},{"text":"All of these tasks can be done with drag and drop.","correct":true},{"text":"Create a new visualization.","correct":false},{"text":"Rearrange and resize visualizations.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]